Forrest, R. E. mss., 1883-1937 LMC 2966
Lilly Library
Forrest, R. E. mss.
1883-1937
Lilly Library
LMC 2966
1 Box
The Forrest, R. E. mss., 1883-1937, consist of the correspondence of author Robert Edward Forrest and his wife, Mary Evangeline (Wild) Forrest, about his writings, as well as related clippings and ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: date unknown
Biographical Note
Robert Edward Treston Forrest, 1835-1914, was an author and an employee in the Public Works Department in India. His works draw upon his experiences living in India.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes correspondence to both R. E. Forrest and his wife, Mary Evangeline (Wild) Forrest, about his writings. Also included are clippings about his published works, an annotated typescript for "Piary's Expiation," and some personal ephemera, such as family photographs and a handwritten poem.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged following the order in which it was received from the bookseller. Upon arrival, each item was individually sleeved within a custom binder box. The archivist chose to group items by type when possible in order to facilitate access and searching.
- Family photographs, 1894-1937 (Box 1)
- Piary's Expiation - annotated typescript, 1908 (Box 1)
- Handwritten copy of review for "The Bond of Blood", October 1899 (Box 1)
- "Testimonials of Mr. R. E. Forrest", 5 June 1883 (Box 1)
- Poem draft, undated (Box 1)
- Notes regarding "Emissary", undated (Box 1)
- Royalties for "The Sword of Azrael", 1908 (Box 1)
- Correspondence to R. E. Forrest, 1885-1903 (Box 1)
- Correspondence to Mary Evangeline (Wild) Forrest, 1914-1915 (Box 1)
- Clippings about Forrest and works, 1914-1915 (Box 1)